Guide to the Howard Zinn Papers TAM.542
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series X: Audio-Visual Material, 1957-2009
  - Subseries X:E: Video VHS, 1986-2007
    - Boston Common: "JFK / Police Commission" (Howard Zinn on Panel), Jan 12, 1992; cuid17483 (Box 81, Video 369)
      Duration: 45 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn at U.C. Santa Cruz, Jan 28, 1992; cuid17484 (Box 81, Video 370)
    - Howard Zinn: "The Gulf War in Moral and Historical Perspective" (Boston College), Feb 5, 1992; cuid17485 (Box 81, Video 371)
    - Howard Zinn: Ames Interview, 1992; cuid17486 (Box 81, Video 372)
      Duration: 106 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn: "Democracy and Disobedience" (CCSU, Hartford CT), Apr 27, 1993; cuid17487 (Box 81, Video 373)
      Duration: 126 Minutes
    - "Legacy": Chief Crazy Horse / Jeff Baker, Nov 11, 1993; cuid17488 (Box 81, Video 374)
      Duration: 21 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn: "Boston Common", Jan 22, 1995; cuid17489 (Box 81, Video 375)
      Duration: 27 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn: "Government for the People?" The Somerville Producers Group Presents Dead Air Live, Jul 18, 1995; cuid17490 (Box 81, Video 376)
    - Howard Zinn: "Building Community in a Class Society" Mankato State University (Mankato, MN), Nov 14, 1995; cuid17491 (Box 81, Video 377)
    - Howard Zinn: Informal Brown Bag Lunch, Nov 16, 1995; cuid17492 (Box 81, Video 378)
    - Howard Zinn: Interview at Santa Rosa, CA, Apr 22, 1996; cuid17493 (Box 81, Video 379)
    - Howard Zinn: "The Possibility of Hope" Resource Center for Nonviolence Santa Cruz, CA, Oct 25, 1996; cuid17494 (Box 81, Video 380)
    - Howard Zinn: "The Uses of History" (University of Minnesota, Duluth), Nov 7, 1996; cuid17495 (Box 81, Video 381)
    - Malden Public Radio: MPR #123, Jan 6, 1997; cuid17496 (Box 81, Video 382)
      Duration: 130 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn at KVCC, Apr 16, 1997; cuid17497 (Box 81, Video 383)
      Duration: 117 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn at KVCC, Apr 16, 1997; cuid17498 (Box 81, Video 383 dup)
      Duration: 109 Minutes, Preservation Note: This is an edited version of cuid17498.
    - Howard Zinn at Santa Cruz High School, Nov 14, 1997; cuid17499 (Box 81, Video 384)
      Duration: 70 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn at Cody's, Nov 14, 1997; cuid17500 (Box 81, Video 385)
    - Howard Zinn: River College, Nov 24, 1997; cuid17501 (Box 82, Video 386)
      Duration: 133 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn Interview at Community Television Santa Cruz, CA, Nov 1997; cuid17502 (Box 82, Video 387)
    - Howard Zinn: Madison, WI, Nov 1997; cuid17503 (Box 82, Video 388)
      Duration: 90 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn: Haverhill High School, Apr 8, 1998; cuid17504 (Box 82, Video 389)
      Duration: 75 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn: "An Economic Bill of Rights" (United Food and Commercial Workers, Union Hall Denver, CO), Oct 5, 1998; cuid17505 (Box 82, Video 390)
      Duration: 71 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn and Studs Terkel (Berkeley), 1998; cuid17506 (Box 82, Video 391)
      Duration: 83 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn and Studs Terkel (Berkeley), 1998; cuid17507 (Box 82, Video 391 dup)
      Preservation Note: Duplicate. Did not digitize.
    - Marx in Soho, 1998; cuid17508 (Box 82, Video 392)
    - Howard Zinn A People's History of the United States Harvard Graduate School of Education, Harvard Education Forum, Feb 17, 1999; cuid17509 (Box 82, Video 393)
    - Howard Zinn at NERC Boston, Mar 1999; cuid17510 (Box 82, Video 394)
    - Howard Zinn: "Kosovo" MSNBC, Apr 3, 1999; cuid17511 (Box 82, Video 395)
      Duration: 47 Minutes
    - "An Evening with Howard Zinn and Clayborne Carson" A Benefit for Speak Out and KPFA at King Middle School (Berkeley CA), May 7, 1999; cuid17512 (Box 82, Video 396)
      Duration: 123 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn Who?: Liberty Hill Foundation, Jun 24, 1999; cuid17513 (Box 82, Video 397)
    - Howard Zinn: Booknotes CSPAN, Jan 26, 2000; cuid17514 (Box 82, Video 398)
    - "People's History: An Evening with Howard Zinn and Ben Affleck", Mar 21, 2000; cuid17515 (Box 82, Video 399)
    - Howard Zinn: DLS Wisconsin Union Theater, Apr 18, 2000; cuid17516 (Box 82, Video 400)
      Duration: 101 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn: "The People's History of U.S. Relations with Cuba" ("Let Cuba Live" Fundraiser for the 11th - Pastors for Peace US/Cuba Friendship Caravan), Oct 4, 2000; cuid17517 (Box 82, Video 401)
    - "War": MSNBC, Sep 19, 2001; cuid17518 (Box 82, Video 402)
      Duration: 11 Minutes
    - "Celebrating Richard A. Cloward's Life and Work", Sep 20, 2001; cuid17519 (Box 82, Video 403)
    - Howard Zinn on the Current Crisis (UVM), Oct 21, 2001; cuid17520 (Box 82, Video 404)
    - Democracy Now: Howard Zinn Speech (Burlington, VT), Oct 2001; cuid17521 (Box 82, Video 405)
      Duration: 57 Minutes, Preservation Note: Edited version of cuid17520.
    - An Evening with Howard Zinn: "People Making History" (Santa Cruz, CA), Nov 2001; cuid17522 (Box 82, Video 406)
    - Howard Zinn: A People's Historian (CWRU, Cleveland, OH), 2001; cuid17523 (Box 82, Video 407)
    - Howard Zinn: Cambridge, Jan 29, 2002; cuid17524 (Box 82, Video 408)
    - Howard Zinn: Alliance for Democracy (Cambridge, MA), Feb 10, 2002; cuid17525 (Box 82, Video 409)
      Duration: 108 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn: "U.S. Foreign Policy, Terrorism and Global Security" (Cambridge, MA), Feb 10, 2002; cuid17526 (Box 82, Video 410)
      Duration: 54 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn: "Bringing Democracy Alive" (Shoreline Community College, Seattle, WA), Apr 10, 2002; cuid17527 (Box 82, Video 411)
    - Howard Zinn with Students of Boston Evening Academy, Jun 2002; cuid17528 (Box 82, Video 412)
      Duration: 55 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn on CSPAN, Sep 1, 2002; cuid17529 (Box 82, Video 413)
      Duration: 176 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn: "You Can't Be Neutral on a Moving Train" - Rough Cut, Sep 2002; cuid17530 (Box 82, Video 414)
    - "Not in Our Name: An Evening of Conscience": Cooper Union (Howard Zinn Appearance), Oct 3, 2002; cuid17531 (Box 83, Video 415)
    - Howard Zinn: "The Legacy of the Civil Rights Movement in the Age of Terrorism" at the Bates College Chapel in Lewiston, ME, Oct 14, 2002; cuid17532 (Box 86, Box 83, Video 416)
    - Howard Zinn: "Terrorism and War" (Brown University, Providence, RI), Nov 14, 2002; cuid17533 (Box 83, Video 417)
    - Now w/ Bill Moyers: Episode 202 (Howard Zinn appearance), Jan 10, 2003; cuid17534 (Box 83, Video 418)
    - Now w/ Bill Moyers: Episode 202 (Howard Zinn appearance), Jan 10, 2003; cuid17535 (Box 83, Video 418 dup)
      Preservation Note: Duplicate of cuid17534. Did not transfer.
    - Howard Zinn: "Tunnel Vision vs. History" at the New School University NYC; Noam Chomsky / "Paths to Peace in the Middle East" at the University of Pennsylvania, Feb 11, 2003/Oct 4, 2002; cuid17536 (Box 83, Video 419)
      Duration: 120 Minutes, Preservation Note: Contains Same Speech as cuid17538 but edited.
    - Howard Zinn: "Tunnel Vision vs. History" at the New School University NYC, Speech by John Schuchardt on behalf of Philip Berrigan (also includes interview with Philip Berrigan from Feb 1997), Feb 11, 2003; cuid17537 (Box 83, Video 420)
      Duration: 115 Minutes, Preservation Note: Contains Same Speech as cuid17538 but edited.
    - Howard Zinn at New School University, Feb 11, 2003; cuid17538 (Box 83, Video 421)
      Duration: 58 Minutes, Preservation Note: Best Version of this recording.
    - Howard Zinn at New School University, Feb 11, 2003; cuid17539 (Box 83, Video 421 dup)
      Preservation Note: Duplicate of cuid17538. Did not transfer.
    - Howard Zinn at New School University (Corrected Sync), Feb 11, 2003; cuid17540 (Box 83, Video 422)
    - Howard Zinn at New School University (Corrected Sync), Feb 11, 2003; cuid17541 (Box 83, Video 422 dup)
    - "Dialogue: Why War?" with Richard Perle and Jessica Tuchman Matthew and Gwen Ifil on the News Hour with Jim Lehrer, Feb 12, 2003; cuid17542 (Box 83, Video 423)
      Duration: 12 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn and Amy Goodman, Feb 19, 2003; cuid17543 (Box 83, Video 424)
      Duration: 102 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn: A People's History of the United States - 92nd Street Y (Aired on Democracy Now Apr 30 and May 1, 2003), Feb [23] 2003; cuid17544 (Box 83, Video 425)
    - The News Hour Live Shot: Jim Lehrer, Howard Zinn, Robert Dallek, Walter Russel Mead and Diane Kunz, Mar 17, 2003; cuid17545 (Box 83, Video 426)
    - Howard Zinn on MSNBC, Jul 13, 2003; cuid17546 (Box 83, Video 427)
      Duration: 5 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn and Woody Harrelson on FSTV, Oct 4, 2003; cuid17547 (Box 83, Video 428)
    - Howard Zinn: Atlanta Book Club, Oct 22, 2003; cuid17548 (Box 83, Video 429)
      Duration: 124 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn Talks About his Book You Can't Be Neutral on a Moving Train (Miami Book Fair International, CSPAN), Nov 8, 2003; cuid17549 (Box 83, Video 430)
    - Howard Zinn: "Books of Our Time" at the Massachusetts School of Law, Nov 11, 2003; cuid17550 (Box 83, Video 431)
      Duration: 60 Minutes
    - Tribute to a Generation: National World War II Reunion - Wartime Stories Stage, WWII Vets as Historians (Howard Zinn, participant), May 27, 2004; cuid17551 (Box 83, Video 432)
    - Howard Zinn and Daniel Ellsberg: Veterans Address the Nation, Jul 23, 2004; cuid17552 (Box 83, Video 433)
    - Howard Zinn on the Daily Show, Jan 6, 2005; cuid17553 (Box 83, Video 434)
    - Howard Zinn on CSPAN, Jan 14, 2005; cuid17554 (Box 83, Video 435)
    - Convocation: "History that Embraces Humanity" (Howard Zinn, speaker), Apr 5, 2006; cuid17555 (Box 83, Video 436)
    - Howard Zinn and James Carroll: "Understanding Our World", Jun 26, 2006; cuid17556 (Box 83, Video 437)
    - Howard Zinn at Brandeis, Jan 2007; cuid17557 (Box 83, Video 438)
    - Howard Zinn on Chet Curtis Report, Feb 16, 2007; cuid17558 (Box 83, Video 439)
    - Brandeis: The Last Teach-In, undated; cuid17559 (Box 83, Video 440)
    - Chomsky on Bill Moyers / Zinn, Moynihan on JFK, undated; cuid17560 (Box 83, Video 441)
    - Emma: Tokyo I, undated; cuid17561 (Box 84, Video 442)
    - Emma: Tokyo II, undated; cuid17562 (Box 84, Video 443)
    - Howard Zinn: Author Series at Cambridge Public Library, undated; cuid17563 (Box 84, Video 444)
    - Howard Zinn at Barnes and Noble, undated; cuid17564 (Box 84, Video 445)
    - Howard Zinn: "The First Amendment: A Historical Perspective", undated; cuid17565 (Box 84, Video 446)
    - Howard Zinn: "On a Moving Train" (lecture plus Q and A session), undated; cuid17566 (Box 84, Video 447)
      Duration: 84 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn Talk: Teachers, undated; cuid17567 (Box 84, Video 448)
    - Howard Zinn on War, undated; cuid17568 (Box 84, Video 449)
    - Marx in Soho (Cuba), undated; cuid17569 (Box 84, Video 450)
    - Marx in Soho (Midwest), undated; cuid17570 (Box 84, Video 451)
    - Marx in Soho: Performed by Normal Marshall, undated; cuid17571 (Box 84, Video 452)
    - "Other Points of View": Interview with Howard Zinn, undated; cuid17572 (Box 84, Video 453)
      Duration: 48 Minutes
    - "The Panama Deception", undated; cuid17573 (Box 84, Video 454)
    - "The Power of People's History": SCL, undated; cuid17574 (Box 84, Video 455)
      Duration: 19 Minutes
    - Royan: Footage for Dennis Mueller, undated; cuid17575 (Box 84, Video 456)
    - The Trials of the AVCO Plowshares: Testimony, undated; cuid17576 (Box 84, Video 457)
    - You Can't Be Neutral on a Moving Train: Rough Cut, undated; cuid17577 (Box 84, Video 458)
      Duration: 8 Minutes
    - You Can't Be Neutral on a Moving Train: 10 Minute Trailer, undated; cuid17578 (Box 84, Video 459)
  - Subseries X:F: Video Other Formats, 1975, undated
    - Sony 1/2" Video Tape: "Cynthia Tape 1", Apr 1, 1975; cuid17579 (Box 84, Half inch video reel 460)
    - Sony 1/2" Video Tape: "David Tape 1", Sep 30; cuid17580 (Box 84, Half inch video reel 461)
    - Sony 1/2" Video Tape: "Linda Tape 1", Oct 1; cuid17581 (Box 84, Half inch video reel 462)
    - Sony 1/2" Video Tape: "Mike Tape 2", Oct 1; cuid17582 (Box 84, Half inch video reel 463)
    - Sony 1/2" Video Tape: [Shechter], undated; cuid17583 (Box 84, Half inch video reel 464)
    - U-Matic Video Cassette: "Student Project, MA Victims of Crime" (includes note from Maribeth Cox), undated; cuid17584 (Box 84, Cassette 465)
    - U-Matic Video Cassette: "High School Kids on the Draft", undated; cuid17585 (Box 84, Cassette 466)
- Series XI: Archived Websites, July 2010-ongoing; cuid17586; 3 websites in 3 archived websites.
  The series contains the archived website documenting the legacy of Howard Zinn, as well as two project websites that Howard Zinn helped found, the Zinn Education Project and Voices of a People's History.
  Accruals
  Websites are crawled semiannually.
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript,streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Arrangement
  Series arranged alphabetically by website title.
  - Howard Zinn, July 2010-ongoing
    In addition to a biography and bibliography for Howard Zinn, the website contains print interviews; essays; commentary and audio and video by Zinn. The People Speak, the documentary based on the live performances of Howard Zinn and Anthony Arnove's Voices of a People's History of the United States is also featured on the website. The website also includes information on the Howard Zinn Memorial Lecture Series; the Howard Zinn Book Fair; centennial celebrations of Zinn's birth in 2022; and obituaries and tributes for Zinn.
  - Voices of a People's History, July 2010-ongoing
    Historical Note
    Voices of a People's History, founded in 2003 by Howard Zinn, Brenda Coughlin, and Anthony Arnove, highlights the history of dissent in the United States through video, speaking engagements, and public readings of primary source materials.
    The website contains news, event listings, educational materials, video of presentations and interviews, and a list of past artists involved in the Voices of a People's History project.
  - Zinn Education Project, July 2010-ongoing
    The Zinn Education Project, founded in 2008 by Howard Zinn and William Holtzman, works to bring A People's History of the United States and other materials for teaching "a people's history" in middle and high school classrooms. The Project is administered by the nonprofits Rethinking Schools and Teaching for Change.
    The website contains resources and lesson plans; This Day in People's History (#tdih) series; "If We Knew Our History" series; and campaigns related to teaching Rosa Parks, Reconstruction, climate change, the 15th Amendment, and Black Lives Matter. The website also includes an Abolish Columbus Day campaign and workshops and conferences offered.